# **Alex Ling**

www.aswling.com
aswling@nyu.edu
(908) 399-5353

#### Education

9/2014 - 5/2018 New York, NY NEW YORK UNIVERSITY (3.812/4.0)

Gallatin School of Individualized Study

Individualized Major focused on design, art history,

visual culture, and marketing

Minor: Business of Entertainment, Media, and

Technology (Stern School of Business)

COURSES Design Studio; Arts Marketing; Contemporary Visual Culture and

the Politics of Images; Media, Technology, and Society; Creative Computing; Communications Lab; Digital Art and New Media;

Digital Media Theory and Practice

ACTIVITIES Founder and President of Gallazine; Emerging Leader Award; Dean's

List; Designer for Embodied Magazine; Work featured in the Gallatin Arts Festival, The Gallatin Review, and Confluence

Aits restivat, the Guildtin Review, and Confluen

8/2016 - 12/2016 Shanghai, China **NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SHANGHAI** (4.0/4.0)

Study Abroad

# **Experience**

9/2017 - Present New York, NY

#### NYU GALLATIN - Graphic Designer

Designer of the 16th volume of *The Literacy Review*. The journal is set for publication in May 2018 and I am responsible for designing the entire issue and related marketing content. I also assist the Gallatin Writing Program in creating web and print material to promote its programs and events.

1/2017 - 8/2017 New York, NY

## AMINO APPS - Design Intern

As a design intern at Amino, I had the opportunity to tackle a variety of projects. I was responsible for spearheading the visual rebrand of Amino's Instagram, which grew its following from 400K+ to 700K+ in three months. Additionally, I created branding for "Amino VIP" and worked with my supervisor to push for a cohesive visual identity across all Amino platforms. I designed and illustrated hundreds of icons, screenshots, and feature graphics for Amino's standalone apps, and also helped design ad campaigns, graphics, animations, deck templates, mobile UI wireframes, and photo-edit user content.

2/2016 - 6/2016 New York, NY

#### VISIT.ORG - Visual Editor Intern

Responsible for curating, photo-editing, and adding images to WordPress to promote Visit.org's organizations. I also assisted with designing decks and organizing Visit.org's image library.

2/2015 - 6/2015 New York, NY

## SCHOLASTIC - Art Dept Admin Assistant

Ensured efficient office organization through invoice and record-keeping, editing contracts, and ordering product samples from Scholastic's warehouse. I also assisted the art department with image and photo research, assembling prototypes, and creating "child-like" drawings and handwriting for products.

7/2013 - 8/2013 New York, NY

#### THE MET - Digital Media Intern

I edited thumbnail images for the museum's new audio guide interface, and verified and organized content from 10+ audio guide tours with 100+ tour stops. At the end of the programs, the interns were divided into groups and each intern was responsible for creating and leading a gallery discussion.

# **Profile**

Hi! I'm Alex. I'm a designer and illustrator who's a senior at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized Study. At NYU, I'm studying design, art history, and marketing, specifically how to visually communicate ideas and interact with audiences. I'm also minoring in the Business of Entertainment, Media, and Technology at the Stern School of Business. I'm passionate about creative media solutions and digital media. I have professional experience in digital and print design, social media, illustration, and making creative content.

## **Tools**

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Premiere, Audition, Arduino, Keynote, InVision

# Skills

Graphic design, illustration, social media, branding, print and book design, digital art, animation, web design, photo-editing and retouching, photography, basic videography

# Favorite Projects

Amino Instagram Rebrand (2017)

"Select" Beer Branding (2017)

FEED Magazine (2017)

Of Mice and Men Redesign (2017)

Homecoming (2017)

Skin Deep (2016)

Zàijiàn (See You Later) (2016)

# Links

LinkedIn	/alexandraling
Tumblr	@alexswling
Github	/aswling
Instagram	@aswling
Twitter	@aswling